sousa kanashimi wo yasashisa ni jibun rashisa wo chikara ni
turn your sadness into kindness, your uniqueness into strength
mayoinagarademo ii arukidashite
even if you get lost, let's start walking
mou ikkai
one more time
dareka no kitai ni zutto kotae
are you really happy
homerarerunoga suki nano desuka
when you're always meeting to someone's expectations?
naritai jibun wo surikaetemo
even if you change to who you really wanna be
egao wa itsudemo suteki desuka
will you always have a great smile?
hajimaridake yume mite okiru
dreaming of only the beginning, I wake up
sono saki nara itsuka jibun no ude de
and someday, I'll live on my own.
souda daiji na mono wa itsumo katachi no nai mono dake
yes, precious things are never in shape
te ni iretemo nakushitemo kizukanumama
you never know what it is when you get it or lose it
sousa kanashimi wo yasashisa ni jibun rashisa wo chikara ni
turn your sadness into kindness, your uniqueness into strength
mayoinagarademo ii arukidashite
even if you get lost, let's start walking
mou ikkai
one more time
That damn Naruto...
The Clouds
are Nice...
The Guy with
No Interest
— C'mon!
— Hurry up with the match!
Finish it up already!
Stand up and start the match!
Evidently, people don't want to
see the minor players' matches
since they were really looking
forward to Sasuke's match...
If people aren't expecting anything
exciting from this battle,
makes no sense
for me to have it.
What? You're giving up, too?
My opponent's a girl again?
Hey, why aren't you moving?!
C'mon, get started!
That kid has had zero fighting spirit
from the beginning...
C'mon! What is he doing?!
C'mon Shikamaru!
Get it together and do it!
If you don't come, I'll go!
Hey! Haven't started yet...
Man, that girl is so gung-ho.
It doesn't really matter if
I become a Chunin or not.
But there's no reason why
a man should lose to a woman.
Well... let's do it!
This guy's quick to run away...
Nor any reason why a man should
rough up a woman.
But I don't want to be
roughed up either.
He's the kind of Ninja that
uses shadows.
Shadow Possession Jutsu.
He's probably trying to lure me into
the trees where there're lots of shadows...
but I won't let him.
Why am I the only one who always
gets a woman for an opponent, dammit?!
Shikamaru! You get her with
a torrent of 16 combination...!
Mind if I sit here?
Huh?
What... you?
Your stomach okay?
What? Wasn't Sasuke's match next?
Shh!
Everything's fine, right, Sakura?
After all, it's Sasuke-kun, right?
R-Right now, I should leave her alone.
It looks like Shikamaru taking part
in this final battle,
it seems like he's in the wrong place.
Don't say that!
I certainly don't think that
he has any great techniques,
but that Shikamaru is
always good at strategising.
That's why I feel like we ended up
in the preliminary round the other day.
Hmm, yeah well...
And after all, he jumped down
into the arena himself.
He seems uncharacteristically driven.
Even he can be passionate
once in a while!
Go! Shikamaru!
Jeez, I envy a cloud being so free...
I guess I pretty much
am completely without desire...
Even the reason why I became a Ninja...
was because I thought
I would have a fun life, ya know...
Get it together!
C'mon Shikamaru!
But... of course, it's not that easy.
What's going on with that stupid face?!
Is he underestimating me?
Ninja Art: Wind Scythe Jutsu!
That's right, with this attack,
my armed attacks also were beaten down.
I see...
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
I've seen that true identity!
Evidently there's a limit to
the stretching and shortening,
changing shape of the shadow...
No matter how much you
change the shape of the shadow,
even when you stretch it,
it can only span up to
the size of your own shadow.
That's right isn't it?
You got it...
Even if I assume that he's made up
the distance,
by stretching his shadow from the edge
of the shadow of the arena wall...
This is the limit to how far
the shadow can stretch.
This is the scope of his attack!
15 meters, 32 centimeters!
She took the distance
with the folding fan.
Temari is stronger at long distance
battles than she is at close range...
the outcome has already been decided.
What? What is that sign...?
That's no sign. That's like, his habit.
Habit...?
He enjoys passing time slowly.
That guy's like an old man.
That's why he likes Shogi and chess
and always makes me be his opponent.
When he's stuck on a move,
he always does that.
Why?
He's working out his strategy.
And, I've never beaten him.
A strategy...
but this is an actual fight.
It's different from a game.
But it's said that formation pieces
that were used to build battle strategy
eventually become
game pieces.
Shikamaru is like a brilliant general.
Wait a minute.
When we grouped the Genin,
I saw his scores.
They were at about the
same level of that Naruto's.
He said that moving his pencil during
written exams at the academy is a pain,
and during the tests,
he always sleeps instead.
A pain...?
He was so good at strategy games,
I felt something wasn't right...
So I had him take an IQ test
under the pretense that it was a game.
And... how did it turn out...?
He was more than brilliant.
With an IQ of over 200,
he's a super genius!
T-Two hundred?!
He's done thinking...
It starts now.
Looks like you've got some
fighting spirit now...
It's pointless to hide!
I wonder if he's really got a strategy...
M-Maybe...
With that he has no approach!
Shikamaru! Go for it!
It's pointless, isn't it?
He'll give up soon.
He hates things
that are a pain in the butt.
You're wrong!
At least, I hope so...
But you may be right...
How long are you going to run away!
Cut it out!
It's no use.
As long as I'm on the
outside of this line,
he absolutely can't catch me...
No, wait! Close call!
You caught on well.
So you were dragging your feet
to wait for the sun to set...
in order to make the surface
of your own shadow larger
by stretching the shadow line of the wall.
As the sun goes down,
the shadows lengthen.
Isn't that so?
That was close! Shikamaru...
But why is he using shadows?
After all, Shikamaru is inside
the shadow of the field.
If there's even a little bit of light,
he can make a shadow within a shadow!
You don't know a thing
about Shikamaru!
A shadow... in a shadow...?
Even if I calculate the height
of the sun now
and the limit to the distance
of the previous attack,
there's no mistaking the distance!
Temari! Up!
I see.
What's this?!
Damn it!
I won't let you escape!
I didn't expect that he would
create extra shadows to reach me
by making a parachute with his jacket...!
He's impressive.
Once I notice the parachute from above,
I'll take my attention off from my feet.
That's a sneaky trick to catch me
off my guard!
However, now it's clear.
Shadow Possession Jutsu is
one in which other shadows are used
to get your opponent,
a skillful technique!
She's dodged this trick too...
Not careful enough in the final stage.
And his opponent is fairly analytical.
She's good at thinking ahead.
If this battle takes too long,
the shadows in the arena will grow,
and his territory will increase.
I'll defeat him with the next one!
Should I make a diversion
with Clone Jutsu...?
Now his shadow is...
Okay!
Clone...
N-No way...!
My... body is...?!
At last...
Shadow Possession Jutsu is a success!
What?!
What's going on...?
That boy...
How much is he planning ahead...?
That's Shikamaru's skill.
Why... won't my body move?!
The shadow shouldn't
have reached this far.
I'll let you take a look behind you...
T-This hole...!
You saw it too, didn't you...?
That hole is the hole Naruto
burrowed and flew out of.
So it's connected to the
big hole in front of you.
I didn't expect that...
a shadow in a tunnel of a hole...
Right.
Pure and simple,
a calculated chess move.
So his purpose to make Temari measure
the limit of the shadow several times
was to lead her to his final trick
of using this hole.
Temari battled on the outside
of the limit of the shadow
that she measured and followed,
but he caught her from behind,
trailed by the shadow she couldn't see...
There is no escape from this.
I-It can't be...
The attack that he used
with the jacket,
was it a device to lead me
to right this spot...?
Was that an under-plot too?!
Why that...?!
Checkmate with the next one.
My body is moving on its own!
I can't resist it!
Before anyone knew it,
they fell under the spell of this match.
That guy with no mark
is quite a darkhorse.
Yes! You did it!
Go! Shikamaru!
Check...
Good grief... I give up!
What?!
See I told you... he'd give up.
Ino doesn't know anything
about Shikamaru.
W-What did you say?!
I've used too much Chakra from Shadow
Possession Jutsu in rapid succession.
I can't hold it another 10 seconds.
I thought of the next trick 200 times.
But I'm out of time...
This has become such a pain.
Doing one match is good...
That guy is a strange one.
The winner is Temari!
ONE JAMPU ichiban SURAMU DANKU kamasu TAISON
One! first, Tyson jumps and slam-dunks
TWO are mo kore mo dosoku de HAGU KISSU I LOVE YOU
Owo! he kisses and hugs everyone randomly and says "I love you"
THREE YOGA wo kiwamemasu KAREE kirai masara san
Three! Masala masters yoga but hates curry
FOUR hetare tougyuushi SANCHESU OREI
Four! Sanchez is a lousy bullfighter, olay!
sekaijuu hora waratteru sora miagete saa tachiagatte
all over the world, the sky's smiling, so look up and smile too
OH YEAH OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah! Oh yeah! Oh yeah!
FIGHT FIGHT FIGHT
Fight! Fight! Fight!
ONE kokuen bori ni bottou bodi ma haattaya san mo
One! Bodimahattaya devotes his time for digging black ships
TWO PEKIN DAKKU waiyaa AKUSHON chari de isogu CHEN RII
Two! peking Duck, action scene, Chen Lee speeds around on his bike
THREE MY KOTEKA daiji ni migakiageru POPO san
Three! Popo loves to polish his coteka
FOUR ote wo haishaku JAPANIIZU PIIPOO
Four! japanese people, now lend me your hand!
sekaijuu hora waratteru sora miagete saa tachiagatte
all over the world, the sky's smiling, so look up and smile too
OH YEAH OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah! Oh yeah! Oh yeah!
FIGHT FIGHT FIGHT
Fight! Fight! Fight!
sekaijuu hora kawatteku minna ganbatte so tachiagatte
all over the world, the sky's smiling, so look up and smile too
OH YEAH OH YEAH OH YEAH
Oh yeah! Oh yeah! Oh yeah!
FIGHT FIGHT FIGHT
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Wow, this is the largest cheer
from the audience ever!
Of course. The featured battle
of this final tournament is about to begin.
Hate to admit it,
but I'm looking forward to it myself.
Hey, Shikamaru.
I can't hear what you said.
There's not a single person who's
not excited about the featured battle.
Next:
"Clash! The Moment Konoha Dances and the Sand Wriggles!"
I can't take my eyes
away from this battle!